There's a tradition in in the training
在教师培训方面有一个传统，
of teachers to say to teachers,
在其中我们会对教师说，
the emotional needs of children are not part
孩子们的情感需求不属于
of your responsibility.
你的责任范围。
There's a tradition in higher education of saying,
在高等教育中，有一个传统是说，
let's factor human feeling out of this equation,
让我们把人的感觉从这个等式中排除，
let's just deal with knowledge
让我们只处理
with facts with theories with the cognitive rational stuff
知识、事实、理论和认知理性的东西，
and leave emotions effect out of the equation.
而把情感效应排除在外。
We know on the basis of a lot of research
我们知道在很多研究的基础上，
that learning doesn't happen under those conditions.
认为学习不会在这些条件下发生。
We have an emotion for example called fear,
例如，我们有一种叫做恐惧的情绪，
that's capable of completely shutting down the mind,
它能够完全关闭思维，
so that people can't learn when fear is
因此，当恐惧在课堂上肆虐时，
rampant in a classroom situation.
人们就无法学习。
But I don't think the education establishment
我不认为教育机构
takes the emotional life of children very seriously.
对儿童的情感生活非常重视。
I think good teachers however are
我认为好的老师
always sensing the emotional life of children
总是能感觉到孩子们的情感世界，
and are always trying to address that,
并总是试图解决这个问题，
good teachers are people
好的老师是这样的人，
who are trying to create a safe space
她试图创造一个安全的空间，
in which children feel hospitably received, feel at home,
让孩子们感到被热情接待，感到宾至如归，
not  just for the sake of making nice on kids.
而不仅仅是为了对孩子好，
but for the sake of helping learning to happen
而是为了帮助学习的发生，
that's what good teachers do.
这就是好老师的工作。
And I have a very strong sense that
我有一个非常强烈的感觉，
one cannot do that for another person
一个人不可能为另一个人这样做，
unless one is doing it for oneself
除非他为自己这样做，
or has someone in one's life who is doing it for you.
或者在他的生活中有人为你这样做。
That is to say that
也就是说，
if a teacher has not taken seriously
如果一个教师没有认真对待
his or her emotional life, his or her spiritual life,
自己的情感生活、精神生活，
his or her relational life,
关系生活的话，
how can such a person
这样的人怎么
possibly do that for the young people
可能会为其所教学的年轻人
with whom you're working.
做这些工作呢。
It doesn't, it just doesn't compute.
这是不可能的，完全不可能的。